#### Contact

07870 625 494 (Mobile) james@jameshogan.co

www.linkedin.com/in/ jameshogan70 (LinkedIn) jameshogan.co/ (Company)

## Top Skills

Marketing Strategy Strategic Planning Digital Marketing

# James Hogan

World-class Marketing Strategy: Helping ambitious businesses to emerge, grow and thrive.

Spelthorne

# Summary

Marketing Consultant: Strategy | Content | Campaigns

Now available for freelance planning projects, big or small.

I love uncovering fresh new insights, ideas and perspectives that inspire meticulous communication strategies and power innovative marketing programmes.

Strategy Director | B2B Marketing | ABM Expert | Agency Planner | Freelance Consultant

## Experience

James Hogan | Marketing Consultant Strategy Director December 2019 - Present (1 year 4 months) Surrey, United Kingdom

Working on a range of freelance planning projects and strategic consulting engagements for ambitious B2B brands and marketing agencies.

Incisive Edge
Head of Planning
October 2017 - December 2019 (2 years 3 months)
London, United Kingdom

Leading marketing strategy and communications planning for high-growth B2B technology brands and professional services companies.

Transmission
Client Strategy Consultant
November 2016 - October 2017 (1 year)
London, United Kingdom

Leading ABM strategy, campaign planning and account management for B2B technology clients combining creative, content and media.

B2B Marketing Awards – nominations

- > Best use of customer insight [WINNER]
- > Best integration of sales and marketing
- > Best customer-centric engagement initiative

#### Kudan

Client Solutions Director January 2014 - December 2015 (2 years) London, United Kingdom

Delivering immersive customer experiences and innovative mobile applications using the latest augmented reality technology.

St Mary's University, Twickenham Visiting Lecturer January 2013 - December 2015 (3 years) London, United Kingdom

Teaching on the Business Management and Professional Development module for the Sport, Health and Fitness Foundation Degree.

Young & Rubicam
Client Development Director
August 2010 - August 2013 (3 years 1 month)
London, United Kingdom

Driving the growth of a branding, design and marketing communications network agency specialising in informing key purchase decisions.

Radley Yeldar
Client Director – Strategist
June 2007 - October 2009 (2 years 5 months)
London, United Kingdom

Helping business clients to communicate effectively through brand identity, corporate reporting, digital media and marketing communications.

Investis Digital
Associate Director
December 2005 - June 2007 (1 year 7 months)
London, United Kingdom

Providing website planning, design and build solutions and online stakeholderbased communications to UK listed companies.

#### Gartner

Senior Account Manager

June 2001 - December 2004 (3 years 7 months)

Hampshire, United Kingdom

Providing management and technology research, advisory and consulting services to key decision-makers in the UK Financial Services sector.

#### Datamonitor

Senior Account Manager

October 1998 - May 2001 (2 years 8 months)

London, United Kingdom

Providing online information solutions to corporate clients to support effective technology and business decision-making.

#### Telstra

**Digital Consultant** 

August 1997 - August 1998 (1 year 1 month)

Advising business customers on emerging technology, digital and web opportunities and supporting the launch of a new B2B product.

#### Converse

Head of Customer Services

1992 - 1996 (4 years)

Managing customer relationships with major UK retailers from sales and order intake through to distribution and aftersales service.

## Education

Lampton School

· (1981 - 1987)